[{"stepName": "Identify Motion of objects", "stepNumber": 1, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "How many moving objects are present?", "options": [4, 5, 7, 0], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "motion", "threejssubstep": 0, "threejssubsubstep": -1, "show1": [""], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084"], "showfc": [], "type": "basic", "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "How many strings are there?", "options": [4, 0, 2, 5], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "motion", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 0, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "showfc": [], "type": "basic", "showfcheading": []}]}, {"stepName": "Write FBD equation for each Moving block", "stepNumber": 2, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "At how many points does the imaginary sphere for red block cuts the strings", "options": [0, 1, 2, 3], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": -100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "type": "basic", "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "answer": 1}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on red block?", "options": ["T\u2081 upwards", "T\u2081 downwards"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "type": "basic", "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of red block in the y-direction", "options": ["+T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "+T\u2081+20=2a\u2081", "-T\u2081+20=2a\u2081", "-T\u2081-20=2a\u2081"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "showfc": ["Upward Forces: T\u2081, ", "Downward Forces: 20", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081"], "type": "basic"}, {"question": "At how many points does the imaginary sphere for yellow block cuts the strings", "options": [0, 1, 2, 3], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": -100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081"], "type": "basic", "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "answer": 1}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on yellow block?", "options": ["T\u2082 downwards", "T\u2082 upwards"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081"], "type": "basic", "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of yellow block in the y-direction", "options": ["+T\u2082+10=a\u2082", "-T\u2082+10=a\u2082", "+T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "-T\u2082-10=a\u2082"], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081"], "showfc": ["Upward Forces: T\u2082, ", "Downward Forces: 10", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082"], "type": "basic"}, {"question": "At how many points does the imaginary sphere for blue block cuts the strings", "options": [0, 1, 2, 3], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 3, "threejssubsubstep": -100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082"], "type": "basic", "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Blue block"], "answer": 1}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on blue block?", "options": ["T\u2082 downwards", "T\u2082 upwards"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 3, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082"], "type": "basic", "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Blue block"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of blue block in the y-direction", "options": ["+40+T\u2082=4a\u2083", "-40+T\u2082=4a\u2083", "+40-T\u2082=4a\u2083", "-40-T\u2082=4a\u2083"], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 3, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082"], "showfc": ["Upward Forces: T\u2082, ", "Downward Forces: 40", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Blue block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083"], "type": "basic"}, {"question": "At how many points does the imaginary sphere for second pulley cuts the strings", "options": [0, 1, 2, 3], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 5, "threejssubsubstep": -100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083"], "type": "basic", "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Second pulley"], "answer": 3}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on second pulley?", "options": ["T\u2081 downwards ", "T\u2081 upwards "], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 5, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083"], "type": "basic", "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Second pulley"]}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on second pulley?", "options": ["T\u2082 upwards ", "T\u2082 downwards "], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 5, "threejssubsubstep": 2, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083"], "type": "basic", "showfc": ["Upward Forces: T\u2081, ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Second pulley"]}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on second pulley?", "options": ["T\u2082 upwards ", "T\u2082 downwards "], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 5, "threejssubsubstep": 3, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083"], "type": "basic", "showfc": ["Upward Forces: T\u2081, ", "Downward Forces: T\u2082, ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Second pulley"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of second pulley in the y-direction", "options": ["-T\u2081+2T\u2082=0", "T\u2081+2T\u2082=0"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 5, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083"], "showfc": ["Upward Forces: T\u2081, ", "Downward Forces: T\u2082, T\u2082, ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Second pulley"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083", "Second pulley: -T\u2081+2T\u2082=0"], "type": "basic"}]}, {"stepName": "Constraint Understanding", "stepNumber": 3, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string if the dog is moving towards right with speed 5 m/s", "options": [-5, 5], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": [0, 5], "show1": [], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string is 5 m/s"], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string if the dog is moving towards left with speed 5 m/s", "options": [-5, 5], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": [0, -5], "show1": [], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string is -5 m/s"], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string if the human is moving towards right with speed 3 m/s", "options": [3, -3], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 3, "threejssubsubstep": [3, 0], "show1": [], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string is -3 m/s"], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string if the human is moving towards left with speed 3 m/s", "options": [-3, 3], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 4, "threejssubsubstep": [-3, 0], "show1": [], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string is 3 m/s"], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of dog in right direction with speed 5 m/s", "options": [-5, 5], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 5, "threejssubsubstep": [3, 5], "show1": [], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s"], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of human in right direction with speed 3 m/s", "options": [3, -3], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 6, "threejssubsubstep": [3, 5], "show1": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s"], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is -3 m/s"], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "Net rate of change of length due to dog moving towards right direction with speed 5 m/s  and human moving in right direction with speed 3 m/s", "options": [-8, -2, 8, 2], "answer": 3, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 7, "threejssubsubstep": [3, 5], "show1": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is -3 m/s"], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is -3 m/s", "Total Rate of change of length of the string due motion of both human and dog is 2m/s"], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of dog in right direction with speed 5 m/s", "options": [-5, 5], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 8, "threejssubsubstep": [-3, 5], "show1": [], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s"], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of human in left direction with speed 3 m/s", "options": [-3, 3], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 9, "threejssubsubstep": [-3, 5], "show1": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s"], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is 3 m/s"], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "Net rate of change of length due to dog moving towards right direction with speed 5 m/s  and human moving in left direction with speed 3 m/s", "options": [-8, 2, 8, -2], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 10, "threejssubsubstep": [-3, 5], "show1": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is 3 m/s"], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is 3 m/s", "Total Rate of change of length of the string due motion of both human and dog is 8m/s"], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of dog in left direction with speed 5 m/s", "options": [5, -5], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 11, "threejssubsubstep": [3, -5], "show1": [], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s"], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of human in right direction with speed 3 m/s", "options": [-3, 3], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 12, "threejssubsubstep": [3, -5], "show1": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s"], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is -3 m/s"], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "Net rate of change of length due to dog moving towards left direction with speed 5 m/s  and human moving in right direction with speed 3 m/s", "options": [2, -2, -8, 8], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 13, "threejssubsubstep": [3, -5], "show1": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is -3 m/s"], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is -3 m/s", "Total Rate of change of length of the string due motion of both human and dog is -8m/s"], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of dog in left direction with speed 5 m/s", "options": [5, -5], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 14, "threejssubsubstep": [-3, -5], "show1": [], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s"], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of human in left direction with speed 3 m/s", "options": [3, -3], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 15, "threejssubsubstep": [-3, -5], "show1": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s"], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is 3 m/s"], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "Net rate of change of length due to dog moving towards left direction with speed 5 m/s  and human moving in left direction with speed 3 m/s", "options": [2, -2, -8, 8], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 16, "threejssubsubstep": [-3, -5], "show1": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is 3 m/s"], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is 3 m/s", "Total Rate of change of length of the string due motion of both human and dog is -2m/s"], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}]}, {"stepName": "Constraint Equations", "stepNumber": 4, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "What is the number of parts which change length in the pink string?", "options": [5, 4, 2, 3], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": -1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083", "Second pulley: -T\u2081+2T\u2082=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083", "Second pulley: -T\u2081+2T\u2082=0"], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"]}, {"question": "What is double derivative of change in l\u2081 for pink string due to red block?", "options": ["+a\u2081", "-a\u2081"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083", "Second pulley: -T\u2081+2T\u2082=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083", "Second pulley: -T\u2081+2T\u2082=0"], "type": "basic", "showfc": ["l\u2081 + l\u2082 = constant"], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"]}, {"question": "What is double derivative of change in l\u2082 for pink string due to the first pulley?", "options": ["+a\u2084", "-a\u2084"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 2, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083", "Second pulley: -T\u2081+2T\u2082=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083", "Second pulley: -T\u2081+2T\u2082=0"], "type": "basic", "showfc": ["l\u2081 + l\u2082 = constant"], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"]}, {"question": "What is the constraint equation for pink string?", "options": ["+a\u2081+a\u2084=0", "+a\u2081-a\u2084=0", "-a\u2081+a\u2084=0", "-a\u2081-a\u2084=0"], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083", "Second pulley: -T\u2081+2T\u2082=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083", "Second pulley: -T\u2081+2T\u2082=0", "Pink string: -a\u2081+a\u2084=0"], "type": "basic", "showfc": ["l\u2081 + l\u2082 = constant", "l\u2081'' = -a\u2081", "l\u2082'' = +a\u2084"], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"]}, {"question": "What is the number of parts which change length in the red string?", "options": [5, 4, 2, 3], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": -1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083", "Second pulley: -T\u2081+2T\u2082=0", "Pink string: -a\u2081+a\u2084=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083", "Second pulley: -T\u2081+2T\u2082=0", "Pink string: -a\u2081+a\u2084=0"], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": ["Red string"]}, {"question": "What is double derivative of change in l\u2081 for red string due to yellow block?", "options": ["+a\u2082", "-a\u2082"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 3, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083", "Second pulley: -T\u2081+2T\u2082=0", "Pink string: -a\u2081+a\u2084=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083", "Second pulley: -T\u2081+2T\u2082=0", "Pink string: -a\u2081+a\u2084=0"], "type": "basic", "showfc": ["l\u2081 + l\u2082 = constant"], "showfcheading": ["Red string"]}, {"question": "What is double derivative of change in l\u2081 for red string due to the firstpulley?", "options": ["+a\u2084", "-a\u2084"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 3, "threejssubsubstep": 2, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083", "Second pulley: -T\u2081+2T\u2082=0", "Pink string: -a\u2081+a\u2084=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083", "Second pulley: -T\u2081+2T\u2082=0", "Pink string: -a\u2081+a\u2084=0"], "type": "basic", "showfc": ["l\u2081 + l\u2082 = constant"], "showfcheading": ["Red string"]}, {"question": "What is net double derivative of change in l\u2081 for red string:", "options": ["+a\u2082+a\u2084", "-a\u2082-a\u2084", "-a\u2082+a\u2084", "+a\u2082-a\u2084"], "answer": [1], "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 3, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083", "Second pulley: -T\u2081+2T\u2082=0", "Pink string: -a\u2081+a\u2084=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083", "Second pulley: -T\u2081+2T\u2082=0", "Pink string: -a\u2081+a\u2084=0"], "type": "basic", "showfc": ["l\u2081 + l\u2082 = constant"], "showfcheading": ["Red string"]}, {"question": "What is double derivative of change in l\u2082 for red string due to the first pulley?", "options": ["+a\u2084", "-a\u2084"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 4, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083", "Second pulley: -T\u2081+2T\u2082=0", "Pink string: -a\u2081+a\u2084=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083", "Second pulley: -T\u2081+2T\u2082=0", "Pink string: -a\u2081+a\u2084=0"], "type": "basic", "showfc": ["l\u2081 + l\u2082 = constant"], "showfcheading": ["Red string"]}, {"question": "What is double derivative of change in l\u2082 for red string due to blueblock?", "options": ["+a\u2083", "-a\u2083"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 4, "threejssubsubstep": 2, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083", "Second pulley: -T\u2081+2T\u2082=0", "Pink string: -a\u2081+a\u2084=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083", "Second pulley: -T\u2081+2T\u2082=0", "Pink string: -a\u2081+a\u2084=0"], "type": "basic", "showfc": ["l\u2081 + l\u2082 = constant"], "showfcheading": ["Red string"]}, {"question": "What is net double derivative of change in l\u2082 for red string:", "options": ["-a\u2084+a\u2083", "+a\u2084-a\u2083", "+a\u2084+a\u2083", "-a\u2084-a\u2083"], "answer": [0], "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 4, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083", "Second pulley: -T\u2081+2T\u2082=0", "Pink string: -a\u2081+a\u2084=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083", "Second pulley: -T\u2081+2T\u2082=0", "Pink string: -a\u2081+a\u2084=0"], "type": "basic", "showfc": ["l\u2081 + l\u2082 = constant"], "showfcheading": ["Red string"]}, {"question": "What is the constraint equation for red string?", "options": ["+a\u2082+a\u2083+2a\u2084=0", "+a\u2082+a\u2083-2a\u2084=0", "-a\u2082+a\u2083+2a\u2084=0", "-a\u2082+a\u2083-2a\u2084=0"], "answer": 3, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083", "Second pulley: -T\u2081+2T\u2082=0", "Pink string: -a\u2081+a\u2084=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083", "Second pulley: -T\u2081+2T\u2082=0", "Pink string: -a\u2081+a\u2084=0", "Red string: -a\u2082+a\u2083-2a\u2084=0"], "type": "basic", "showfc": ["l\u2081 + l\u2082 = constant", "l\u2081'' = -a\u2082-a\u2084", "l\u2082'' = -a\u2084+a\u2083"], "showfcheading": ["Red string"]}]}, {"stepName": "Final Answers", "stepNumber": 5, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "What are the final accelerations, tensions and normal reactions?", "options": ["a\u2081= -14, a\u2082= -55, a\u2083= 98, a\u2084= 14, T\u2081= 23, T\u2082= 123, T\u2083= 394", "a\u2081= 2.31, a\u2082= 2.31, a\u2083= -6.92, a\u2084= -2.31, T\u2081= 24.62, T\u2082= 12.31, T\u2083= 49.23", "a\u2081= -18, a\u2082= 18, a\u2083= 49, a\u2084= 123, T\u2081= -14, T\u2082= 246, T\u2083= 18", "a\u2081= -21, a\u2082= 345, a\u2083= 18, a\u2084= 12, T\u2081= 197, T\u2082= -21, T\u2083= 16"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "motion", "threejssubstep": 1000, "threejssubsubstep": 1000, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083", "Second pulley: -T\u2081+2T\u2082=0", "Pink string: -a\u2081+a\u2084=0", "Red string: -a\u2082+a\u2083-2a\u2084=0"], "showfc": [], "showfcheading": [], "tobeshown": 1, "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, a\u2084, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-20=2a\u2081", "Yellow block: +T\u2082-10=a\u2082", "Blue block: +40-T\u2082=4a\u2083", "Second pulley: -T\u2081+2T\u2082=0", "Pink string: -a\u2081+a\u2084=0", "Red string: -a\u2082+a\u2083-2a\u2084=0", "Final Answers: a\u2081= 2.31, a\u2082= 2.31, a\u2083= -6.92, a\u2084= -2.31, T\u2081= 24.62, T\u2082= 12.31, T\u2083= 49.23"]}]}]